{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Silicon dioxide","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium hydroxide","Calcium magnesium carbonate","Potassium nitrate"],"question":"What chemical has the formula SiO2?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"C. S. Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Jack Vance","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Chronicles of Narnia'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neil Gaiman","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","H. P. Lovecraft","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'American Gods'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neoclassicism","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Dutch Golden Age","High Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"The Grand Odalisque\" by Jean Auguste Dominique Ingres is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Israel","Turkey","Brazil"],"question":"Havana is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Medina","incorrectAnswers":["Mecca","Jerusalem","Baghdad"],"question":"What is the name of the Islamic holy city where the prophet Muhammad was buried?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'S&M'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["Paraguay","Chile","Bolivia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Uruguay?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lucy Maud Montgomery","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Munro","Lewis Carroll","Margaret Atwood"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Anne of Avonlea'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"6,371 km","incorrectAnswers":["637 km","63 km","63,710 km"],"question":"What is the approximate radius of the Earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Absolute Monarchy","incorrectAnswers":["Democracy","Constitutional Monarchy","Parliamentary Democracy"],"question":"What kind of government dominated most of Europe during the 17th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Samuel L. Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["John Travolta","Michael Douglas","Johnny Depp"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Jules Winnfield in Pulp Fiction?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Toronto Maple Leafs","incorrectAnswers":["Toronto Yankees","Toronto Bucks","Toronto Colts"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Toronto?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Silver","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Platinum","Bronze"],"question":"In Western cultures, what is the traditional gift for a 25th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Italian","incorrectAnswers":["Spanish","French","English"],"question":"What was the nationality of Marco Polo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denver ","incorrectAnswers":["Columbus","Austin","Sacramento"],"question":"Which US state capital is known as the mile high city?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Sopwith Camel","incorrectAnswers":["The Supermarine Spitfire","The Curtiss Warhawk","The P54 Mustang"],"question":"Which type of British fighter plane shot down 1,294 enemy aircraft in World War One?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Black","incorrectAnswers":["White","Red","Pink"],"question":"In snooker, what is the color of the last ball to be potted?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Dwayne Johnson","Shah Rukh Khan","Gérard Depardieu"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Batman and The Departed?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Mexico","Indonesia"],"question":"Where is Lake Maracaibo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Seco Herrerano","incorrectAnswers":["Tequila","Nsafufuo","Unicum"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Panama?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"On trees","incorrectAnswers":["Under water","In the ground","On grasses"],"question":"Where do cashews grow?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Larry Holmes","incorrectAnswers":["George Foreman","Mike Tyson","Sugar Ray Robinson"],"question":"Who was the only boxer to knock out Mohammed Ali?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Christina Aguilera","incorrectAnswers":["Britney Spears","Mariah Carey","Whitney Houston"],"question":"Who sung the 1999 pop song 'Genie in a Bottle'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Martin Heidegger","incorrectAnswers":["Denis Diderot","Jean-Jacques Rousseau","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'He who thinks great thoughts, often makes great errors'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Shadowboxing","incorrectAnswers":["Make-believe boxing","Doxing","Ghostboxing"],"question":"What is the term used when a boxer practices fighting against an imaginary opponent?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Marley's Ghost","incorrectAnswers":["Christmas Past","Christmas Present","Christmas Future"],"question":"Who was the first ghost appear to scrooge in the dickens classic 'a Christmas Carol'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Parkinson's","incorrectAnswers":["Multiple Sclerosis","ALS","Alzheimer's"],"question":"Which disease causes tremors, and is often treated with hand exercises to improve motor skills?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Humphrey Bogart","incorrectAnswers":["James Stewart","John Belushi","Kevin Spacey"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Sam Spade in The Maltese Falcon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Margaret Atwood","incorrectAnswers":["Jules Verne","William Gibson","Frederik Pohl"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Handmaid's Tale'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Macau","incorrectAnswers":["Hong Kong","Goa","Cape Belia"],"question":"Which Portuguese colony reverted to China in December 1999?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nicolae Ceausescu","incorrectAnswers":["Slobodan Milošević","Josef Stalin","Colonel Gaddafi"],"question":"Which dictator was executed by firing squad on Christmas Day 1999?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gangs of New York","incorrectAnswers":["Broadcast News","Terms of Endearment","Sweet Smell of Success"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'William 'Bill the Butcher' Cutting'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Green","Black"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Puerto Rico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lightning","incorrectAnswers":["Prehistoric life","Wine and winemaking","Movement in relation to human anatomy"],"question":"What is fulminology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Do not speak against the Sun","incorrectAnswers":["To dare is to do","Every man is the maker of his own fortune","I came, I saw, I conquered"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Adversus solem ne loquitor' translate into English?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chicago","incorrectAnswers":["Gangs of New York","The Hours","The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2002?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pyongyang","incorrectAnswers":["Busan","Seoul","Chongjin"],"question":"What is the capital of North Korea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Croquet","incorrectAnswers":["Tennis","Badminton","Billiards"],"question":"Which Game Makes Use Of Hoops","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'We Are the Champions'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Satan","incorrectAnswers":["Jesus","Dante","Judas"],"question":"Who is the protagonist of Milton's Paradise Lost?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A story focusing on a turn-of-the-century prospector in the early days of the business.","incorrectAnswers":["A screenwriter develops a relationship with a faded film star determined to make a return.","A human soldier is sent from 2029 to 1984 to stop an almost indestructible cyborg killing machine.","The life of the lawyer who became the famed leader of the Indian revolts against the British rule."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie There Will Be Blood?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Stand'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nikolai Gogol","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia Woolf","Alexander Pushkin","Ayn Rand"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mirgorod'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Study in Scarlet'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sigmund Freud","incorrectAnswers":["Francis Bacon","George Washington","Francisco Pizarro"],"question":"Which influential neurologist founded psychoanalysis, which involved the investigation of the subconscious, dreams and human mind?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Living Daylights","incorrectAnswers":["From Russia With Love","Goldfinger","Quantum of Solace"],"question":"Which James Bond theme song was performed by A-ha?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"212","incorrectAnswers":["100","32","169"],"question":"What is the boiling point of water in Farenheit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Away From Keyboard","incorrectAnswers":["Award For Knowledge","Ahoy, Fellow Kid","Another Fancy King"],"question":"What do the letters 'AFK' mean on internet chats?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Botticelli","incorrectAnswers":["Michelangelo","Leonardo da Vinci","Raphael"],"question":"Which Italian artist shocked 1485 Florence with his large nude painting of the birth of a goddess?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Reykjavik","incorrectAnswers":["Helsinki","Oslo","Copenhagen"],"question":"What is the capital of Iceland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sashimi","incorrectAnswers":["Risotto","Pizza","Lasagne"],"question":"Which of these dishes isn't Italian?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sedimentary Rocks","incorrectAnswers":["Igneous Rocks","Metamorphic Rocks","Fossils"],"question":"What type of rock is formed from fragments of preexisting rocks or by the deposition of mineral or organic particles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Robert Burns","incorrectAnswers":["JM Barrie","Robert Louis Stevenson","James Hogg"],"question":"Who wrote Auld Lange Syne?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cronus","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Hercules","Mythos"],"question":"Who was the father of Zeus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pacific Ocean","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantic Ocean","Indian Ocean","Arctic Ocean"],"question":"Which ocean features the Sulu Sea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Angels","incorrectAnswers":["Prophets","Demons","Saints"],"question":"In the Islamic faith, what are Harut and Marut?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chihuahua","incorrectAnswers":["Sonora","Nuevo Leon","Michoacan"],"question":"What Mexican state is home to the city of Ciudad Juarez?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cherry","incorrectAnswers":["Apple","Peach","Plum"],"question":"What fruit is associated with the spirit called Kirschwasser?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Hawaii","Cuba","Madagascar"],"question":"Which island country lies to the East of Mauritius?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Monsters, Inc.","incorrectAnswers":["Metropolis","Into the Wild","The Green Mile"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'In order to power the city, beasts have to scare children so that they scream.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"No Country for Old Men","incorrectAnswers":["Atonement","Juno","Michael Clayton"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2007?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Newton's Laws of Motion","incorrectAnswers":["Darwin's Theory of Evolution","Einstein's Theory of Relativity","Mendel's Laws of Genetics"],"question":"Which of the following was a major scientific discovery of the 17th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Curry","incorrectAnswers":["Aaron Paul","Mark Hamill","Richard Burton"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Rocky Horror Picture Show and Charlie's Angels?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"After his son is captured and taken to Sydney, a clownfish sets out on a journey to bring him home.","incorrectAnswers":["A prince cursed to spend his days as a monster sets out to regain his humanity.","After he becomes a quadriplegic, an aristocrat hires a young man to be his caregiver.","A high school student is sent thirty years into the past in a time-traveling car."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Finding Nemo?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Embryology","incorrectAnswers":["Endocrinology","Pathology","Radiology"],"question":"What is the name of the process that is concerned with the development of the fertilized egg and the growth of the fetus?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tuvalu","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Malawi","Togo"],"question":"Funafuti is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","incorrectAnswers":["\"Man! I Feel Like a Woman!\" by Shania Twain","\"Chimpan-A to Chimpan-Z\" by Troy McClure","\"Gimme More\" by Britney Spears"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"When I was a young boy my father took me into the city to see a marching band.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Menes","incorrectAnswers":["Rene Descartes","Imhotep","Diogenes"],"question":"Which influential historical person was an Egyptian pharaoh who united Upper and Lower Egypt to found the First Dynasty?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Soccer","incorrectAnswers":["Baseball","Basketball","Tennis"],"question":"What is the most popular sport in Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Haruki Murakami","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Umberto Eco","Søren Kierkegaard"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Kafka on the Shore'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pavlova ","incorrectAnswers":["Peach Melba","Eton Mess","Creme Brulee"],"question":"Which dessert was created in honour of a famous ballet dancer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Eel","incorrectAnswers":["Salmon","Tuna","Octopus"],"question":"What is the name of a snake-like fish that is often used in sushi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Lindisfarne Mead ","incorrectAnswers":["Long Island Iced Tea","Camomile Tea","Dandelion & Burdock"],"question":"Which drink do you associate with a holy island in Northumberland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nicaragua","incorrectAnswers":["Honduras","El Salvador","Costa Rica"],"question":"In which country are the largest two lakes in Central America located, including Lake Managua?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Fight Club","incorrectAnswers":["Hotel Rwanda","North by Northwest","Rocky"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'An insomniac and a soap maker form an underground organisation that evolves into much more.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Mersey","incorrectAnswers":["The Rhine","The Tyne","The Thames"],"question":"What river is Liverpool on?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Central Asia","Southeast Asia"],"question":"Where in the world are radishes originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Michelangelo","incorrectAnswers":["Gustav Klimt","‎Pablo Picasso","El Greco"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Creation of Adam\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You shall not pass!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Forget it, Jake, it's Chinatown.\"","\"After all, tomorrow is another day!\"","\"Very nice!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","The Clash","The Police"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'We Will Rock You'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Hunchback of Notre Dame","incorrectAnswers":["Aladdin","The Lion King","The Little Mermaid"],"question":"Which animated Disney film includes a villain named Claude Frollo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"People's Republic of China","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Mongolia","Philippines"],"question":"Which of these countries borders North Korea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gin","incorrectAnswers":["Tequila","Whiskey","Rum"],"question":"What liquor is popularly paired with tonic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"prison management and criminal rehabilitation","incorrectAnswers":["rays, usually ionising radiation","music","the classical Chinese literary masterpiece Dream of the Red Chamber"],"question":"What is Penology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Sherman Tank","incorrectAnswers":["The Herman Tank","The Berman Tank","The German Tank"],"question":"The American M4 tank is better known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Truman Capote","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Jordan","Philip K. Dick","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Breakfast at Tiffany's'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Corsica","incorrectAnswers":["St Helena","Sicily","Jersey"],"question":"On which island was Napoleon Bonaparte born?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Volvo","incorrectAnswers":["Toyota","Fiat","Mazda"],"question":"Which automaker offers a V90 model?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the album 'Viva la vida or Death and All His Friends'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eurythmics","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which British music duo released the song 'Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This)'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The merciless rivalry between Formula One rivals James Hunt and Niki Lauda.","incorrectAnswers":["The lives of mob hitmen, a boxer, a gangster and his wife, and a pair of bandits intertwine in four tales.","A stand-up comedian embarks on a downward spiral that leads to the creation of an iconic villain.","An Army officer serving in Vietnam is tasked with assassinating a renegade Special Forces Colonel."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Rush?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Misunderstood","incorrectAnswers":["Made of wood","Gone for good","Placed in the hood"],"question":"Complete the lyrics from The Animals' song: 'I'm just a soul whose intentions are good, oh, Lord, please don't let me be'...","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fyodor Dostoyevsky","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Leo Tolstoy","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Gambler'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hubble","incorrectAnswers":["Bubble","Toil","Trouble"],"question":"What is the name of the space telescope that was placed in Earth's orbit in 1990?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Symbiosis","incorrectAnswers":["Parasitism","Syncronicity","Parallelism"],"question":"What is the word for a relationship between two different types of organism which live together for their mutual benefit?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Bhagavad Gita","incorrectAnswers":["The Upanishads","The Ramayana","The Puranas"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu scripture that contains the dialogue between Krishna and Arjuna?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Senegal","incorrectAnswers":["Uruguay","Bosnia and Herzegovina","Brunei"],"question":"Dakar is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Iodine","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium","Chlorine","Iron"],"question":"What element is lacking in a diet when goitre occurs?","difficulty":"hard"},